Linda Pershing "Ribbon around the Pentagon" collection
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
- Series 3: Other Ribbon project participants, 1984-1989
  - Ribbon project interviews
    - New York
      - Photos of Erica Kimball Weiss and another Ribbon panel maker, with panels, in Ithaca, NY, May 3 to 6, 1989, AFC 2018/007: PH012; 21 color transparencies (35mm slides); Photographs attributed to Linda Pershing (Box 2)
      - Ruth Kahn interview, Ithaca, NY (1 of 2), May 3, 1989, AFC 2018/007: SR068; 1 audiocassette (90 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing
      - Ruth Kahn interview, Ithaca, NY (2 of 2), May 3, 1989, AFC 2018/007: SR069; 1 audiocassette (90 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing; First recording on Side A of SR069. See also the second recording on Side A, plus all of Side B.
      - David Kay interview, Ithaca, NY, May 3, 1989, AFC 2018/007: SR069; 1 audiocassette (90 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing; Second recording on Side A, plus all of Side B, on SR069. See also the first recording on Side A.
      - Photos of Erica Kimball Weiss, Ribbon panels, and a view of Ithaca Commons in Ithaca, NY, May 3 to 6, 1989, 4 color photographic prints (3 1/2 x 5 in.); Photographs attributed to Linda Pershing (Box-folder 1/5)
      - Photos of Erica Kimball Weiss and another Ribbon panel maker, with panels, in Ithaca, NY, May 3 to 6, 1989, AFC 2018/007: PH011; 15 color transparencies (35mm slides); Photographs attributed to Linda Pershing (Box 2)
      - Erica Kimball Weiss interview, Ithaca, NY (1 of 2), May 6, 1989, AFC 2018/007: SR029; 1 audiocassette (90 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing; Side B of SR029. See also Side A.
      - Erica Kimball Weiss interview, Ithaca, NY (2 of 2), May 6, 1989, AFC 2018/007: SR070; 1 audiocassette (90 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing; Side A of SR070. See also Side B.
      - Lois Lounsbery interview, Ithaca, NY (1 of 2), May 6, 1989, AFC 2018/007: SR070; 1 audiocassette (90 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing; Side B of SR070. See also Side A.
      - Lois Lounsbery interview, Ithaca, NY (2 of 2), May 6, 1989, AFC 2018/007: SR071; 1 audiocassette (90 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing
    - Texas
      - Photos of Ariadne "Ari" Wright with her panels, developed November 1985, AFC 2018/007: PH013; 5 color transparencies (35mm slides); Photographs attributed to Linda Pershing (Box 2)
      - Ariadne "Ari" Wright interview, Austin, TX, November 29, 1985, AFC 2018/007: SR072; 1 microcassette (60 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing
      - Anne Long interview, Austin, TX (1 of 2), December 4, 1985, AFC 2018/007: SR073; 1 microcassette (60 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing
      - Anne Long interview, Austin, TX (2 of 2), December 4, 1985, AFC 2018/007: SR074; 1 microcassette (60 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing
      - Photos of Mary Beard with her panels, developed December 1985, AFC 2018/007: PH014; 12 color transparencies (35mm slides); Photographs attributed to Linda Pershing (Box 2)
      - Mary Beard interview, Austin, TX (1 of 2), December 6, 1985, AFC 2018/007: SR075; 1 microcassette (60 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing
      - Mary Beard interview, Austin, TX (2 of 2), December 6, 1985, AFC 2018/007: SR076; 1 microcassette (60 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing
      - June and Bill Thompson interview, Linda Pershing's house, Austin, TX (1 of 4), March 24 to 25, 1987, AFC 2018/007: SR079; 1 microcassette (60 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing
      - June and Bill Thompson interview, Linda Pershing's house, Austin, TX (2 of 4), March 24 to 25, 1987, AFC 2018/007: SR078; 1 microcassette (60 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing
      - June and Bill Thompson interview, Linda Pershing's house, Austin, TX (3 of 4), March 24 to 25, 1987, AFC 2018/007: SR080; 1 microcassette (60 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing
      - June and Bill Thompson interview, Linda Pershing's house, Austin, TX (4 of 4), March 24 to 25, 1987, AFC 2018/007: SR077; 1 audiocassette (90 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing
  - Ribbon panels
    - Ribbon panel, "Organdy apron," before August 1985, AFC 2018/007: AR002; 1 textile (18 1/4 x 35 1/4 in.; appliqué); Made by Lucile Miller (Box 8)
      Linda Pershing's description: "Lucile (spelled with one 'L') Miller, Justine Merritt's mother, organdy apron panel, applique, Denver, CO. Lucile said in an interview with Linda Pershing that the apron represented the many years she was a homemaker and mother, roles that she valued. See pp. 198-9 in Pershing's book."
    - Ribbon panel, "Madre de los Oprimidos," before August 1985, AFC 2018/007: AR003; 1 textile (18 x 45 in.; embroidery and appliqué); Made by Sister Maria Louisa Valdez (Box 8)
      Linda Pershing's description: "Sister Maria Louisa Valdez, OLVM, Mora, NM. Madre de los Oprimidos, Ayúdanos a Alcanzar le Libertad Perdida (Mother of the Oppressed, Help Us Restore or Reclaim Lost Liberty), embroidered and applique. The Mexican legend of the Our Lady of Guadalupe appearing to Juan Diego. See p. 128 in Pershing's book."
    - Ribbon panel, "My Dog," before August 1985, AFC 2018/007: AR004; 1 textile (18 3/4 x 34 1/2 in.; paint); Made by Unknown (Box 9)
      Linda Pershing's description: "My Dog. Presumably painted by a child. No name or place or date. (Is the dog in the blue hillside or water?)."
    - Ribbon panel, "Dancing lobsters," before August 1985, AFC 2018/007: AR005; 1 textile (17 1/4 x 37 1/2 in.; knitted); Made by Penelope Day (Box 9)
      Linda Pershing's description: "Penelope Day, Nantucket, MA. Dancing lobsters, knitted or woven. Inscription on the back: 'I live in a beautiful parts of the country, on the island of Nantucket, thirty miles out at sea. I felt that my piece should be representative of something native to Nantucket and the natural beauty and special conditions that exist here as they don't anywhere else on Earth. I wanted to do something for children, something fun. They are our future and it is too terrible to live without hope for tomorrow. --Penelope Day.' See pp. 126-7 of Pershing's book."
    - Ribbon panel, "Hot air balloons and flowers," before August 1985, AFC 2018/007: AR006; 1 textile (18 x 40 3/4 in.; needlework); Made by Sister Madeleine J. Perkins (Box 9)
      Linda Pershing's description: "Sister Madeleine J. Perkins, RSM, Chicago, IL. Hot air balloons and flowers. Inscription on the back: 'Hot air balloons - excitement, fun, color, freedom; Flowers - nature, beauty, creation, sweet scents; People to enjoy it all!; O God, help us to work for world peace!!'"
    - Ribbon panel, "Peace Sign and Spirit Mask," before August 1985, AFC 2018/007: AR007; 1 textile (18 3/4 x 35 3/4 in.; appliqué); Made by Fred Janvrin (Box 10)
      Linda Pershing's description: "Fred Janvrin ... Anchorage, Alaska. Peace Sign and Spirit Mask. Inscription on the back: ... A peace sign trying to be a Spirit Mask. This piece reflects my fondness for Alaskan Native art and spirit masks in particular with their feathers blowing in the wind. Also marked: 'P.M. 2 of 21,' and 'NRC 44.'"
    - Ribbon panel, "Weaving is Peaceful," before August 1985, AFC 2018/007: AR008; 1 textile (18 1/2 x 38 in.; woven sampler); Made by Kerstin Tribby (Box 10)
      Linda Pershing's description: "Kerstin Tribby, Ithaca, NY. Weaving is Peaceful, woven sampler."
    - Ribbon panel, "Constellations," March 8, 1985, AFC 2018/007: AR009; 1 textile (18 1/4 x 36 3/4 in.; embroidery, appliqué, and quilting); Made by Jane Van De Bogart (Box 10)
      Linda Pershing's description: "Jane Van De Bogart, 3-8-85, Woodstock, NY. Constellations. Embroidered, applique, and quilted. Written on the back: 'The night sky has been an endless source of wonder...of worlds beyond me...of something to aspire higher for...of fascination.' Also written on the back: 'Jane Van De Bogart April 1985.'"
    - Photos of Ribbon panels by Ariadne "Ari" Wright, Phyllis Ochs, and other Ribbon makers, circa 1984 to 1989, AFC 2018/007: PH015; 42 color negatives (35mm); 21 color photographic prints (3 1/2 x 5 in.) (Box 7, Box-folder 1/6)
    - Photos of Ribbon panels, developed May 1985, 3 color photographic prints (3 1/2 x 5 in.) (Box-folder 1/7)
    - Photos of Ribbon panels, developed March 1986, AFC 2018/007: PH016; 120 color transparencies (35mm slides) (Box 2)
    - Photos of Ribbon panels, developed April 1986, AFC 2018/007: PH017; 65 color transparencies (35mm slides) (Box 3)
    - Photos of Ribbon panels, developed May 1986, AFC 2018/007: PH018; 15 color transparencies (35mm slides) (Box 3)
    - Photos of Ribbon panels, circa June 1984, AFC 2018/007: PH019; 23 color transparencies (35mm slides); Photographed by June Thompson (Box 3)
    - Photos of Ribbon panels, developed April 1987, AFC 2018/007: PH020; 31 color transparencies (35mm slides); Photographs attributed to June Thompson (Box 3)
    - Photos of Ribbon panels, developed February 1988, AFC 2018/007: PH021; 159 color transparencies (35mm slides) (Box 4)
    - Photos of Ribbon panels, developed March 1988, AFC 2018/007: PH022; 30 color transparencies (35mm slides) (Box 4)
    - Photos of Ribbon panels, developed April 1989, AFC 2018/007: PH023; 37 color transparencies (35mm slides) (Box 4)
    - Photos of Ribbon panels, developed July 1989, AFC 2018/007: PH024; 9 color transparencies (35mm slides) (Box 5)
    - Photos of Ribbon panels, undated, AFC 2018/007: PH025; 2 color transparencies (35mm slides) (Box 5)
    - Photos of Ribbon panels (partial frames), developed between April 1986 and February 1988, AFC 2018/007: PH026; 12 color negatives (35mm) (Box 7)
  - Ribbon events
    Photographs depicting the original "Ribbon around the Pentagon" ceremony in Washington, D.C., as well as the other events leading up to and following the ceremony between 1984 and 1989. Listed chronologically.
    - Photos of Justine Merritt, Lucile Merritt, Mary Frances Jaster, Mary Jo Peterson, and other Ribbon panel makers at an unidentified event, circa 1984 to 1989, 4 black-and-white photographic prints (4 x 5 in.) (Box-folder 1/8)
    - Photo of David Kay and other Ribbon panel makers working on panels at Ithaca Commons in Ithaca, NY, June 1984, AFC 2018/007: PH027; 1 color transparency (35mm slide); Photographs attributed to Mary Milne (Box 5)
    - Photo of a Ribbon ceremony in New York, NY, May 1985, AFC 2018/007: PH028; 1 color transparency (35mm slide) (Box 5)
    - Photos of an unidentified Ribbon event, circa June 1985, AFC 2018/007: PH029; 2 color transparencies (35mm slides) (Box 5)
    - Photo of an unidentified Ribbon event, June 1985, AFC 2018/007: PH030; 1 color transparency (35mm slide) (Box 5)
    - Photos of Justine Merritt at the "Ribbon around the Pentagon" ceremony in Washington, D.C., August 4, 1985, 2 color photographic prints (3 1/2 x 5 in.); Photographed by Judy Holzer and Carol Karnitsky (Box-folder 1/9)
    - Photos of Justine Merritt at the "Ribbon around the Pentagon" ceremony in Washington, D.C., August 4, 1985, AFC 2018/007: PH031; 2 color transparencies (35mm slides) (Box 5)
    - Photo of David Kay displaying a panel by Mary Milne at the "Ribbon around the Pentagon" ceremony in Washington, D.C., August 4, 1985, 1 color photographic print (3 1/2 x 5 in.); Photographed by Mary Milne (Box-folder 1/10)
    - Photo of David Kay and other Ribbon panel makers at the "Ribbon around the Pentagon" ceremony in Washington, D.C., August 4, 1985, AFC 2018/007: PH032; 3 color transparencies (35mm slides); Photographed by Mary Milne (Box 5)
    - Photos of the "Ribbon around the Pentagon" ceremony in Washington, D.C., August 4, 1985, AFC 2018/007: PH033; 25 color transparencies (35mm slides) (Box 5)
    - Photos of the "Ribbon around the Pentagon" ceremony in Washington, D.C., August 4, 1985, 2 color photographic prints (3 1/2 x 5 in.) (Box-folder 1/11)
    - Photo of Ribbon panels displayed at Ithaca Commons in Ithaca, NY, August 1985, AFC 2018/007: PH034; 1 color transparency (35mm slide) (Box 5)
    - Photos of Justine Merritt, Mary Frances Jaster, and other Ribbon panel maker at unidentified event, developed May 1986, AFC 2018/007: PH035; 3 color transparencies (35mm slides) (Box 5)
    - Photos of a Hands Across America march, developed May 1986, AFC 2018/007: PH036; 3 color transparencies (35mm slides) (Box 5)
    - Photos of Ribbon panels exhibited at the Textile Museum in Washington, D.C., June 1986, AFC 2018/007: PH037; 101 color transparencies (35mm slides) (Box 5)
      Linda Pershing's description: "In 1986 artists Joan Monastero and Anita Wetzel curated an impressive exhibit of one hundred Ribbon panels at the Textile Museum in Washington, D.C. These slides are photos of that exhibition."
    - Photos of Ribbon panels exhibited at the Textile Museum in Washington, D.C. (partial frames), June 1986, AFC 2018/007: PH038; 3 color negatives (35mm) (Box 7)
    - Photos of Ribbon panels on display around McElroy Fountain in Oakland, CA, developed April 1987, AFC 2018/007: PH039; 8 color transparencies (35mm slides) (Box 5)
    - Photos of Ribbon panels on display around McElroy Fountain in Oakland, CA, developed April 1987, AFC 2018/007: PH040; 5 color transparencies (35mm slides); Photographs attributed to June Thompson (Box 5)
    - Photos of Ribbon panels exhibited in the Blagg-Huey Library atrium at Texas Woman's University in Denton, TX, April 26 to 27, 1987, AFC 2018/007: PH041; 22 color transparencies (35mm slides) (Box 5)
    - Photos of the Peace Fair in Austin, TX, May 1987, AFC 2018/007: PH042; 18 color transparencies (35mm slides) (Box 5)
    - Photos of Ribbon panels exhibited at the 9th National Conference of the National Women's Studies Association, "Weaving Women's Colors: A Decade of Empowerment," at Spelman College in Atlanta, GA, June 24 to 28, 1987, AFC 2018/007: PH043; 25 color transparencies (35mm slides) (Box 6)
    - Photos of the Betty Mihalaros award ceremony in honor of Justine Merritt in San Francisco, CA, June 4 to 5, 1988, AFC 2018/007: PH044; 33 color transparencies (35mm slides); Photographed by Mary Milne (Box 6)
    - Photos of the Betty Mihalaros award ceremony in honor of Justine Merritt in San Francisco, CA, June 4 to 5, 1988, AFC 2018/007: PH045; 18 color transparencies (35mm slides) (Box 6)
    - Photo of a small gathering with Justine Merritt in Ithaca, NY, developed July 1989, AFC 2018/007: PH046; 1 color transparency (35mm slide) (Box 6)
  - Video programs featuring the "Ribbon around the Pentagon" ceremony
    - Ribbon 'Round the Pentagon, 1984, AFC 2018/007: MV001; 1 videocassette (120 min.); Produced by Barb Britain; First recording on MV001. See also second recording.
    - The Peace Ribbon, 1986, AFC 2018/007: MV001; 1 videocassette (120 min.); Produced by David Sabbath; Second recording on MV001. See also first recording.
  - Video program featuring other quilting activism projects
    - A Stitch for Time: The Boise Peace Quilt Project, 1987, AFC 2018/007: MV004; 1 videocassette (120 min.); Produced by Nigel Noble; Second recording on MV004. See also first and third recordings.
  - Copies of study data collected by Gabriella Miller and Carol Cockrell, 1985, 8 folders; Designed by Gabriella Miller and Carol Cockrell
    Each folder contains the compiled responses to one question from a questionnaire created by Texas Woman's University researchers Gabriella Miller and Carol Cockrell. The researchers had the questionnaire printed in a 1985 issue of Ribbon Newsletter, and participants joined the study by returning their responses in the mail. Participants are anonymized as numbers 1-805.
    - Question 1 (Box-folder 1/12)
    - Question 9 (Box-folder 1/13)
    - Question 10 (Box-folder 1/14)
    - Question 12 (Box-folder 1/15)
    - Question 13 (Box-folder 1/16)
    - Question 14 (Box-folder 1/17)
    - Question 17 (Box-folder 1/18)
  - Statements and photos submitted to Lark Books
    A selection of 35mm slides and submission forms sent to the publisher Lark Books by Ribbon panel makers, for inclusion in the book The Ribbon: A Celebration of Life (1985).
    - Forms submitted to Lark Books, circa January to May 17, 1985, 1 folder; Written by Eileen R. Gavel, Martha Obenshain, Ethelyn G. Ormondroyd, Nancy Perry, Jane J. Smith, and anonymous (Box-folder 1/19)
    - Photos of panels and events submitted to Lark books, May 8, 1984 to May 1985, AFC 2018/007: PH047; 5 color transparencies (35mm slides); Photographs attributed to Ethelyn G. Ormondroyd, Nancy Perry, Jane J. Smith, and anonymous (Box 6)
    - Photo of panels and events submitted to Lark books / Eileen R. Gavel,, developed May 1985, AFC 2018/007: PH048; 1 color transparency (35mm slide); Photographed by Jim Provine (Box 6)
- Series 4: Research materials, 1985-1995
  Original output from Linda Pershing's research. This series includes photographs originally collected from other sources but curated by Linda Pershing for her teaching lectures. Includes copies of Linda Pershing's scholarly publications on the Ribbon project. Also includes one cleaning microcassette.
  - Teaching materials
    - "Excellent slides for presentations," circa August 1985 to 1989, AFC 2018/007: PH049; 12 color transparencies (35mm slides) (Box 6)
    - "Ribbon slides for class talks," circa August 1985 to 1989, AFC 2018/007: PH050; 36 color transparencies (35mm slides) (Box 6)
  - Publications
    - Feminist Theory and the Study of Folklore, edited by Susan Tower Hollis, Linda Pershing, M. Jane Young, 1993, 1 monograph, signed by Linda Pershing; © University of Illinois Press (Box 1)
    - Sew to Speak: The Fabric Art of Mary Milne, by Linda Pershing, 1995, 1 monograph, signed by Linda Pershing; © University Press of Mississippi (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous research materials
    - Cleaning microcassette, 1 cleaning microcassette (Box 1)
- Series 5: Donation notes, 2018
  Notes written by Linda Pershing at the time of the collection's donation to the American Folklife Center at the Library of Congress. The notes were interspersed with materials as labels. The information from the notes has been incorporated into this finding aid.
  - Linda Pershing's donation notes, circa May 14, 2018 (Box-folder 1/20)
Bibliography
Published works in this collection
Merritt, Justine. A Cup of Cool Water: Meditations on the Life of Christ. Creative Core, n.d.
Pershing, Linda. Sew to Speak: The Fabric Art of Mary Milne. Jackson: University Press of Mississippi, 1995.
Tower Hollis, Susan, Linda Pershing, and M. Jane Young (eds.). Feminist Theory and the Study of Folklore. Urbana: University of Illinois Press, 1993.
Other related publications
Lark Books staff, Marianne Philbin (eds.). The Ribbon: A Celebration of Life. Asheville, N.C.: Lark Books, 1985.
Pershing, Linda. The Ribbon around the Pentagon: Peace by Piecemakers. Knoxville: University of Tennessee Press, 1996.